blueshift.com 2019-07-12

# Privacy Policy

**BLUESHIFT LABS, INC. PRIVACY POLICY**

**Effective Date: July 9, 2019**

This privacy policy covers our collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through blueshift.com including our platform (“Platform”) at app.getblueshift.com (collectively known as “Services”), owned and operated by Blueshift Labs, Inc. (“Blueshift,” “we,” or “us”). Blueshift knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This privacy policy describes how we collect, receive, use, store, share, transfer, and process your personal information, as well as your rights in determining what we do with the information that we collect or hold about you. Blueshift is a third party service provider and collects information under the direction of its clients, and has no direct relationship with individuals whose data its processes. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect offline. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our Terms of Service. The use of information collected through our Service shall be limited to the purposes under this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service to our customers.

**How We Use and Collect Your Information**

**Personal Information:**

We receive and store any information you knowingly provide to us when you browse our website, submit information or contact us. Such as your name, email address, and browser information. If you become a customer of ours, additional information will be obtained to provide you service and process your payments. We may provide this information to our Partners. If we do so, such information may be non-personal or in aggregate form to prevent individual identification.

In using our Services as our customer, we will also receive and store any information you choose to provide us with respect to your customers (“End User Customers”). The End User Customer information (“End User Customer Information”) we receive and store typically includes names and email addresses of your customers along with any other information you choose to provide us.

We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service; the provisions in this Policy, and the service agreements cover transfers to such subsequent third parties such as credit card processors.

**Cookies and Similar Technologies**

When you use our Services, your browser may send us certain information about you as described below.

**Log File Information:**  Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page on our Service. When you access the Service, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information.

**Cookies Information:**  We along with our partners, affiliates, and service providers use cookies. We may send one or more cookies — small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters — to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets us learn about your behavior and usage patterns when you are on our Service. A cookie may also convey non-personal information about how you browse a partner website to us. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Service. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Please note that if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our services.

Our partners, affiliates, and service providers use cookies to: (a) monitor the effectiveness of our Service and the offerings of our partners; (b) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (c) diagnose or fix technology problems; (d) and allow our business partners to deliver advertisements to you as described below. We do not control these third party tracking technologies or how they may be used.

Click [here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) to learn more about how to change your browser settings and manage your cookies

**Clear Gifs:**. We along with our partners, affiliates, and service providers use clear gifs. When you access our Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our Users. No personal information from your Blueshift account is collected using these clear gifs. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our Service, and make Blueshift better for our Users and partners.

** ** **JavaScript:**  We along with our partners, affiliates, and service providers use JavaScript. JavaScript is a dynamic object oriented computer programming language. JavaScript is used to understand user behavior on our website.

**E-Tags:**  We along with our partners, affiliates, and service providers use E-Tags. E-Tag is a technology that is part of the standard HTTP protocol that allows our website to validate temporary storage (cache) of our pages and images. This ensures that you are viewing the latest version of our website since your last visit.

**Third Party HTML5 (Local Storage):**  Our partners, affiliates, and service providers use Local Storage (LS) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSs.

**Advertising**

We may partner with third parties to to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

**How We Share Your Information**

Blueshift will not rent or sell your personal information to others.

We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of Blueshift (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). Any personal information you elect to make publically available on the Service, such as posting comments on our blog page, will be available to others online.. If you remove information that you have made public on our Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at  **support@blueshift.com**. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

We share your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities such as [payment processing or providing customer service]. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us, pursuant to written instructions. In such cases, these companies must abide by our data privacy and security requirements, and are not allowed to use personal information they receive from us for any other purpose. 

We may share non-personal information (such as usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain Blueshift services. Non-personal information may be stored indefinitely.

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our website in addition to other endorsements. If we do so, it will be with your consent. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at  **support@blueshift.com**.

In certain situations, Blueshift may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Blueshift will disclose your information where required to do so by law such as to comply with a subpoena or legal process, or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law or in response to a reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) in good faith to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Blueshift, our Users or others.

We may buy or sell/divest/transfer the company (including any shares in the company), or any combination of its products, services, assets and/or businesses. Your information such as customer names and email addresses, and other User information related to our Service may be among the items sold or otherwise transferred in these types of transactions. We may also sell, assign or otherwise transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, acquisitions, bankruptcies, dissolutions, reorganizations, liquidations, similar transactions or proceedings involving all or a portion of the company, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

**User Access and Choice  **

We respects your control over your information and, upon request, we will confirm whether we hold or are processing information that we have collected from you. You also have the right to amend or update inaccurate or incomplete personal information, request deletion of your personal information, or request that we no longer use it. Under certain circumstances we will not be able to fulfill your request, such as if it interferes with our regulatory obligations, affects legal matters, we cannot verify your identity, or it involves disproportionate cost or effort, but in any event we will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and provide you an explanation. In order to make such a request of us, please email us at support@blueshift.com.

Please note that for personal information about you that we have obtained or received for processing on behalf of a separate, unaffiliated entity–which determined the means and purposes of processing, all such requests should be made to that entity directly. We will honor and support any instructions they provide us with respect to your personal information. 

**Marketing Preference / Opt Out**

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page, or you can contact us at support@blueshift.com.

We will also send you service related email announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You do not have an option to opt out of these emails, which are not promotional in nature.

**Storage and Processing**

Information collected through our Service may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Blueshift or its subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities. Blueshift may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world

**How We Protect Your Information**

Blueshift is concerned with protecting your privacy and data. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at  **support@blueshift.com**.

**Advertising Choice and Control**

As described in this Privacy Policy, third parties may use cookies and similar tracking technologies to collect information and infer your interests for interest-based advertising purposes. If you would prefer to not receive personalized ads based on your browser or device usage, you may generally express your opt-out preference to no longer receive tailored advertisements by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note that you will continue to see advertisements, but they will no longer be tailored to your interests

**Information Related to Data Collected through the Platform Service**

  * **End User Choice and Access**

We collect information for our customers; if you are an End User of one of our customers and would no longer like to be contacted by our customers that use our service, please contact them directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our customers.

An End User who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query with our customer(s) that use our Service directly. If our customers request that we remove such data, we will respond to your request within a reasonable time.

  * **Customer Access**

If you are a customer of ours, you can review, and correct, update or delete inaccuracies to the information about you that Blueshift keeps on file by logging into your account. Alternately, you can contact us directly at  **support@blueshift.com**. We will respond to your request to access within reasonable time.

Blueshift will retain your information and information we process on behalf of your clients for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, this information is retained for a period of 12 months after you terminate our Service, however, a Customers request to have this information deleted sooner will be honored within a reasonable time. We will also retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Children’s Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Blueshift does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to access or use the Service or to provide any personal information to Blueshift. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at  **support@blueshift.com**.

**Notification Procedures**

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Service, as determined by Blueshift in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Links to Other Websites**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from the Service, including the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website or service, including those that have a link or advertisement on our website, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes social media features, such as a Facebook button and widgets, the Twitter button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These features may collect your IP address, track which pages you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing these features.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

If we change our privacy policies and procedures materially, we will post those changes on the Service to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. When we change the policy in a material manner we will let you know via a prominent notice on our Web site, prior to the change becoming effective and update the ‘effective date’ at the top of this page.

**  EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield**

Blueshift participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S Privacy Shield Framework. Blueshift is committed to subjecting all personal information received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List [www.privacyshield.gov/list](http://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Blueshift is responsible for the processing of personal information it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Blueshift complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal information from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Blueshift is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Blueshift may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. ** **

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please contact us at  **support@blueshift.com** , or send mail to:

Blueshift Labs, Inc.  
231 Sansome St Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94104
